Guide to the Aḥmad Zakī Abū Shādī Family Papers AD.MC.065
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Correspondence, 1912-2000
  - Abu Shadi, Ahmed Zaki, 1912-1954
    - Chronological files, (2), 1924 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Abou el-Seoud, Ahmed, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Abu Shadi, Annie, 1921-1931 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Abu Shadi, Annie, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Abu Shadi, Annie, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Abu Shadi, Annie, 1934-1937 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Abu Shadi Family: regarding estate of Muhammed Bey, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Abu Shadi Family: unidentified, 1941-1945 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Abu Shadi, Muhammed Bey, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Abu Shadi, Muhammed Bey, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Abu Shadi, Muhammed Bey, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Abu Shadi, Muhammed Bey, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Abu Shadi, Muhammed Bey, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Abu Shadi, Muhammed Bey, 1917-1918 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Abu Shadi, Muhammed Bey, 1920-1922 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Abu Shadi, Ramzy (Amin), 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya, 1948-1950 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya, 1951-1953 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Anglo-Egyptian Union, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Apis Club (Bee World), 1920-1922 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Arousy, M.E. (Cairo), 1922 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Bagoury, M.E. (Alexandria), 1922 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Barratt, Gilbert (Sheffield), 1920-1921 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Educational Book Co., Ltd., 1921 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Encyclopedia Brittanica, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Friends (including Wadie Philistin), 1924-1954 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Harker, Leonard (Apis Club), 1924 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Hassib, Muhammed Bey, 1906-1914 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Law, Arthur (Apis Club), 1924 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Maher, Ali (Prime Minister of Egypt), 1938-1942 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Mikhail, Kyriakos, 1923, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1921-1922, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1952-1954 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Move, 1922: Franklin and Gale, auctioneers (Wallingford) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Move, 1922: Thomas Cook and Son (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Naguib, Amina (mother), 1912-1916 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Naguib family (including Hosny, Soleiman), 1912-1942 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Rouby, Wafeya (sister), and family, 1912-1931 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Abu Shadi, Annie, 1918-1946
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed Zaki, 1918-1927 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed Zaki, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed Zaki, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed Zaki, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed Zaki, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed Zaki, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Bamford, Eveline (sister), 1918 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Sidebottom, Martha (sister), 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Abu Shadi, Safeya, 1941-2000
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed Zaki, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed Zaki, 1949-1952 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Abu Shadi, Annie, 1937-1945 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Abu Shadi, Ramzy (Amin), 1958 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Badawi, Dr. Mustafa Mohamed (Oxford), 1992 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Condolence letters upon death of father, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Egypt, Embassy of (Washington, DC), 1972-1979 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Egypt, miscellaneous, 1956-1996 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Ghobashi, Ibraham (Gaithersburg, MD), with clippings about Ahmed Abu Shadi, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Ibrahim, Radwan, 1961-1967 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Kerrou, A.M. (Tunis), 1992 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Moussa, Raouf Salama, 1986-1992 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Naguib, Hosny, 1949-1956 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Naguib, Soleiman, 1947-1952 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Najm, Prof. Mohammed Yousif (American University of Beirut), 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Publishers of Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi poetry, Beirut, 1998-2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Saudi Arabia, Embassy of, Washington: Faisal, Crown Prince / King, 1947-1975 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Saudi Arabia, Embassy of, Washington: Ibn Aqeel, Ibrahim, 1954-1959 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Saudi Arabia, Embassy, of Washington: Invitations, printed, undated, circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Saudi Arabia, Embassy of, Washington: miscellaneous, 1954-1959, and undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Saudi Arabia, Embassy of, Washington: United Nations, Delegation to, 1948-1959 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Slim, Hadi (regarding publication of Abu Shadi poetry), Beirut, 1985-1988 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - University of Utah (regarding Abu Shadi archive), 1976-1999 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Wanly, Adham, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Wellman, Constance (stepmother), 1948 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, unidentified [Wadie Philistin?], 1960-1962 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, unidentified [Wadie Philistin?], 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, unidentified: admirers, "Hassan" and others, 1945, and undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Garnett, Hoda (Abu Shadi), with Leila and Abdel Monem Saleh, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Writings, 1900-2004
  - Abu Shadi, Ahmed Zaki, 1909-1955
    - Manuscript text: Eulogy and memorial poems for father, 1925-1926 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript text: "Chat with a Sacred Bee," (English), undated, circa 1946 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript text: "The Free Nagrouz" / "Al-Najruz al-hara' " (photocopy), 1952 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript text: "From the Canticles of Life / Min anāshīd al-hīyah", 1953 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript text: various poems, in folder titled "Isis and other poems", 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Manuscript text; "An introduction to the Philosophy of Religion" (notes), circa 1950s (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Memoir fragments, 1945 and undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper articles, 1950-1955 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Poetry: 'Anda al-fajr, manuscript, 1327 A.H., circa 1909 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Poetry: "By the Statue of Saad Zaghlul," (manuscript, with accompanying letter to Safeya, 1949) (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Poetry: "Cleopatra: Egypt's Heroine," (manuscript draft, Arabic), undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Poetry: Songs of Love (photostat copies, Arabic), 1953 and undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Poetry: miscellaneous, Arabic, 1945 and undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Poetry: miscellaneous, typescript, English, 1953 and undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Poetry: poem addressed to Safeya, on her birthday, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Publications, lists of, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Speeches: address for Saudi delegation to the U.N., manuscript draft, Nov.-Dec. 1946 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Speeches: "Understanding the People of Egypt," New York University, February 1952 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Voice of America: unidentified script, dedicated to Safeya, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Voice of America: "Islam in the Atomic Age" (Spirit of Islam, #3), manuscript draft, April 1954 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Voice of America: "The American Islamic School" (Spirit of Islam, #20), manuscript draft, April 1955 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Voice of America: scripts: "American Democracy in Light of Islam" (10 episodes), 1953 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Voice of America: scripts: "The Spirit of Islam" (18 episodes), 1954 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Voice of America: scripts: "Tales of the Unbelievable" (4 episodes), 1954 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Voice of America: scripts, typed lists of, 1954-1955 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Voice of America script (?), unidentified, dedicated to Safeya, 1949
    - Voice of America: general, 1950-1955 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Abu Shadi, Safeya, 1944-1960
    - Poetry, manuscript (loose leaves, with corrections), undated, circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Poetry, manuscript (loose leaves), 1944 and undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Poetry, manuscript (loose leaves), 1945 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Poetry, manuscript (in composition books), 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Poetry, manuscript (in composition book, titled "Picture Book"), 1945-1946 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Poetry, manuscript (loose leaves), 1947-1954 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Poetry, manuscript (loose leaves), 1955-1959 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Poetry, manuscript, English, 1947-1955 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Poetry, manuscript: composition book, Farouk the First University, 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Poetry, published (Minbar al-Sharq, and elsewhere), 1945-1960 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Poetry, from others, transcribed, in notebooks (1), circa 1940s (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Poetry, from others, transcribed, in notebooks (2), circa 1940s (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Poetry, from others, transcribed, in notebooks (3), circa 1940s (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Poetry, from others, transcribed, in notebooks titled "Poetic translations", 1945-1946 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, unidentified, 1935 and undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Naguib, Mustafa (brother of Amina Naguib), photostat copies, 1900 and undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Philistin, Wadie: published articles, about Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi, 1949-1959, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Philistin, Wadie: published articles, about literature in general, sent by S. Slim, 1997-2002 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Photographs, 1904-1993, and undated
  - Abu Shadi, Ahmed Zaki, 1910-1959, 1985, and undated
    - Abu Shadi, Mohammed Bey, and unidentified man, during Hajj, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Abu Shadi, Mohammed Bey, and Ahmed Zaki, portraits, circa 1900s (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: studio portraits, circa 1900-1910 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: studio portraits, 1917-1929 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: portraits, 1930-1946, and undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: portraits, United States, circa 1947-1950 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: medical students and colleagues, Egyptian, circa 1913-1925 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: medical colleagues, United Kingdom, 1916 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: in medical laboratories, office, Egypt, circa 1930s (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: with scientists, doctors, and others, Egypt, circa 1930s (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: with various colleagues, 1920s-1930s (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: beekeeping, England, 1912-1922, and undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: with colleagues at Bee Conference, Cairo, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: Beekeeping League, Egypt, 1935-1938 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: beekeeping in Egypt, circa 1939-1941 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: beekeepers and beehives, New York, 1946-1950 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: in United States, 1946-1952 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: dinner in his honor, Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, New York, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: with friends, United States, circa 1947-1951 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: at United Nations, with Andrei Gromyko, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: Voice of America, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: gravesite, Fort Lincoln Cemetery (Maryland), 1955 and 1985 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed: photographs of paintings of, 1959 and undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Abu Shadi family: as group, 1904-1993
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed and Annie: home in Ealing (Cairn Street), 1917 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed and Annie: wedding portrait, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed and Annie: with friends, Benson, Oxfordshire, U.K., 1921-1922 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed and Annie: with Safeya, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Abu Shadi, Annie, with Safeya, in Suez, 1923-1924 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Abu Shady, Annie and children, circa 1920s (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Abu Shadi, children: Egypt, circa 1930s (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Abu Shadi, children: Egypt, circa 1940-1946 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Abu Shadi family: general (folder 1), circa 1920s (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Abu Shadi family: general (folder 2), circa 1920s-1930s (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Abu Shadi family: at monuments at Giza, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Abu Shadi family: beehives in Egypt, circa 1920s and 1930s (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Abu Shadi family: portraits, Alexandria, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Abu Shadi family: voyage to U.S. on board S.S. Vulcania, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Abu Shadi family: United States, circa 1947-1951 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Abu Shadi family: house in Washington, DC, circa 1951-1955 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Abu Shadi family: copy negatives and contact prints, with note from Hoda, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Abu Shadi family: copy prints, made by Hoda, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Abu Shadi family: copy prints, made by Hoda, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Abu Shadi and Bamford family members, as numbered by Hoda, 1904-1946 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Abu Shadi family: copy prints, of images from 1910s (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Abu Shadi family: individuals, 1914-1961, and undated
    - Bamford, Annie: copy prints, undated, originals, circa 1910-1920 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Bamford, Annie: colorized portrait, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Abu Shadi, Annie, 1923-1946 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Bamford family: gravesite, England, undated, circa 1920 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Bamford family: children, 1924-1926 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Bamford and Pollard families, United Kingdom and Canada, 1927-1950 and undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Abu Shadi, Ahmed, with Constance Wellman, 1948-1952 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Abu Shadi, Hoda: as infant, circa 1925-1927 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Abu Shadi, Hoda; as child with beehives (Matarieh), 1930 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Abu Shadi, Hoda: school class portrait, Alexandria, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Abu Shadi, Hoda: Egypt, 1942-1946 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Abu Shadi, Hoda: United States, 1946-1954 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Abu Shadi, Hoda: United States, with Saudi diplomats, circa 1947 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Abu Shadi, Hoda: United States, with sister, Safeya, undated, circa late 1940s (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Abu Shadi, Hoda: portraits, undated, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Abu Shadi, Hoda: U.S. Navy, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Abu Shadi, Ramzy, 1961 and undated, plus one postcard, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Abu Shadi, Ramzy: with United Nations peacekeeping forces, Lebanon, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: childhood, circa 1923-1926 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: school portraits, 1938 and undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: with friends, 1937-1942 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: with friends (matted and framed images), circa 1940-1945 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: with friends, circa 1940-1946 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: Egypt, general, circa 1940-1946 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: family or friends of, Egypt, circa 1940-1947 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: United States, circa 1946-1960 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: graduation portrait, George Washington University, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: Saudi Arabia Embassy (Washington), reception, with Prince Faisal ibn Abdulaziz; Ambassador Asad al-Faqih, and others, undated, circa 1946 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: Saudi Arabia Embassy (Washington), reception for Prince Faisal ibn Abdelaziz and Prince Abdel Muhsin ibn Abdelaziz, with Ambassador al-Faqih, Sheikh Suleiman al-Aqeel, and Safeya pictured, undated, circa 1946-1947 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: Saudi Arabian Embassy (Washington), various receptions and events, unidentified, undated, circa 1947-1955 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: Saudi Arabian Embassy (Washington): staff, diplomats, family members, circa 1950s (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: Saudi Arabian Embassy (Washington): Ambassador Asad al-Faqih and family, undated, circa 1947-1954 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: Saudi Arabian Embassy (Washington): friends, Abdulrazak al-'Ateeq, 1951-1957, and undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: friends, male, circa 1950s (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: friends, unidentified wedding, Washington, D.C., with Hoda and Safeya as guests, circa 1950s (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: studio portraits, circa 1950s (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: pictures of, general, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: unidentified outdoor event, Safeya with group of men, signing of guestbook, unidentified, circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: friends and their families, circa 1955-1962 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: United Nations, Safeya in attendance at General Assembly, undated, circa 1955-1965 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: business trip to Cairo, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: general, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: Saudi Arabia Embassy (Washington): reception for Ambassador to Venezuela, Muhammed Muhtasib (photograph with invitation), February 1967 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Abu Shadi, Safeya: Voice of America, undated image of Safeya behind microphone, as well as separate image of Arabic correspondent, Margaret Pennar, circa 1960s (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Abu Shadi, Wafeya (sister of Ahmed Zaki), 1924-1932, and undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Others: relatives and friends, 1926-1971, and undated
    - Naguib, Soliman, 1926, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Philistin, Wadie: during visit to United States, with Abu Shady family, and other unidentified man, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Philistin, Wadie, with Hassan Salama, Edward Sadek, and others, during visit by Ramzy Abu Shady to Cairo, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Philistin, Wadie: with wife and children, 1956-1962 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Wanly Brothers (Adham and Seif): with family members, art works, 1945 and undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Wanly, Adham, 1946-1949, and undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Wanly, Seif, 1945-1971 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - General, 1926-1978, and undated
    - Apollo Group, portrait, 1934 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Germanus, Gyula (Julius): inscribed to Abu Shadi, circa 1920s (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Harb, Talaat, portrait, inscribed, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - King Farouk I, of Egypt, circa 1930s (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Al Mahdiyeh, Sayyedeh Munira (singer, actress): portrait, undated, circa 1920s (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Mūsá, Nabawīyah, seated with group, undated, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Nājī, Ibrāhīm, 1933, and undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Shābbī, Abū al-Qāsim, portrait inscribed to Apollo Magazine, circa 1932-1933 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Tagore, Rabindranath: group portrait during visit to Egypt, including Abu Shady, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Unindentified people, circa 1930s (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Abdulaziz bin Abdulrahman (Ibn Saud), King of Saudi Arabia, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Arafat, Yasser, chairman of P.L.O. during visit to United Nations, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Faisal ibn Abdulaziz, Prince: visit to United Nations with Saudi delegation, including Sheikh Hafez Wahba and Ambassador Asad al-Faqih, September 1946 and undated (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Faisal ibn Abdelaziz, Prince: event at Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, New York, includes portrait of Saudi delegation signed by each member, and other images that include Ahmed Zaki Abu Shadi, Sheikh Hafiz Wahba, and others, November 1946 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Faisal ibn Abdelaziz, Prince: at United Nations, Lake Success, NY, pictured with members of various Arab delegations, including Faris el-Khoury, Charles Malik, Abdul Rahman Azzam, Mahmoud Hassan Pasha, Fadhil Jamali, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Faisal ibn Abdelaziz, Prince: at United Nations, New York, with various delegates, including Alexander Cadogan, Andrei Gromyko, and Canadian delegates Roch Pinard and L.R. Beaudoin, April 1947, and undated (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Faisal ibn Abdelaziz, Prince: with Dean Acheson, likely at reception at Saudi Embassy in Washington, also pictured with Muhammed ibn Faisal, and Abdel Muhsin ibn Abdelaziz, undated, circa 1947 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Faisal ibn Abdelaziz, Prince: signed photograph of Faisal enjoying snow, and undated images, including with Prince Edward (Duke of Windsor), 1956-1962, and undated (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Faisal ibn Abdelaziz, King of Saudi Arabia: visit to United Nations, New York, and meetings with Secretary General U Thant, June 1966 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Mohammed ibn Faisal al Saud, Prince, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Nawaf ibn Abdelaziz al Saud, Prince, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Mosque on Massachusetts Avenue NW, Washington, DC, 1957 and undated (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Nasser, Gamel Abdel, undated portrait, and at United Nations, and other images, circa 1960 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Saud ibn Abdulaziz, King of Saudi Arabia: during U.S. visit including with President Eisenhower, circa 1954 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Sadat, Jehan: "Faith and Hope Ball," Washington, DC, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Various: scenes in and around Alexandria, Egypt, 1942-1945, and undated (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Various: United Nations, 1955-1964 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Albums
    - Album, with snapshots and passport photos of Abu Shadi family. 12 leaves, double-sided, with ownership mark of "Silvia Abushady" [Safeya] (Box OS-1, Object 9)
    - Album gifted to Hoda from Safeya, 1941, showing mostly the two and their girlhood friends, Alexandria, circa 1942-1946 (Box OS-2, Object 12.2)
    - Album, random photos of family, from Egypt, undated, mostly circa 1942-1946 (Box OS-2, Object 12.1)
    - Album of Hoda and her husband, many images of husband, 1947-1949, and undated (Box OS-2, Object 12.3)
    - "Post card album" mostly Hoda, Ramzy, and other family members, Egypt., undated, circa 1940-1946 (Box OS-2, Object 12.4)
    - Album, containing images of Safeya, Hoda, Ramzy, and friends, in New York and Washington, D.C., 1947-1951 (Box OS-7, Object 37)
    - "Sphinx and Pyramids at Guizeh"[sic]. Egyptian themed postcards, and a few small pictures of places in Egypt, undated, circa 1920s-1940s (Box OS-2, Object 12.5)
  - Oversized prints
    - Group portrait, including A.Z. Abu Shadi, possibly with government ministers, Alexandria, undated, circa 1930s (Box OS-5, Folder 1)
    - Group portrait, with A.Z. Abu Shadi and daughter, Safeya, in center, with colleagues of Abu Shadi, in Alexandria (inscription in Arabic on verso), December 1926 (Box OS-5, Folder 2)
    - Group portrait of members of Apollo Group, including A.Z. Abu Shadi, Ibrahim Naji, and others, names added on frame surrounding image, 1936 (Box OS-5, Folder 3)
    - Group portrait of members of Apollo Group, Alexandria, with names of members written in margins, September 11, 1937 (Box OS-5, Folder 4)
    - Portrait of singer Umm Kulthum, with orchestra, performing on stage, undated, circa late 1930s (Box OS-5, Folder 5)
    - Group portrait, Red Crescent, with Prince Muhammad Ali, and Muhammad Abu Shadi Bey (back row, left), among others, undated, circa 1910s-1920s (Box OS-5, Folder 6)
    - Group portrait (unidentified), with Muhammad Abu Shadi Bey seated in front row, center, undated, circa 1910s-1920s (Box OS-5, Folder 7)
    - Group portrait, doctors and staff from hospital in Port Said, Egypt, with A.Z. Abu Shadi, seated at front row, left, July 1926 (Box OS-5, Folder 8)
    - Group portrait, unidentified (Port Said?), with A.Z. Abu Shadi seated, front row, left, 1925 (Box OS-5, Folder 9)